所有电动机的基本物理原理是磁力。那么我们
The fundamental physical principle underlying all electric motors is magnetism. So, let’s
快速回顾我们对磁铁的了解。
quickly review what it is we know about magnets.
每个磁铁都有一个南极和一个北极，因为北极被吸引了
Every magnet has a south pole and a north pole, so called because the north pole is attracted
到了我们这个星球的北极。如果我像这样把两块磁铁放在一起，我们就知道了
to the north pole of our planet. If I put two magnets together like this, we know that
相反的极点吸引和相似的磁极互相排斥。现在，让我们假设我们拿两个
opposite poles attract and like poles repel each other. Now, let’s imagine we take two
将磁铁放在另一个的顶部并固定它们，使顶部磁铁自由
magnets and lay one on top of the other and pin them so that the top magnet is free to
旋转。然后，会发生类似的磁极排斥而顶部磁铁倾向于旋转
rotate. Then, what happens is that the similar poles repel and the top magnet tends to rotate
使顶部磁铁的北极位于底部磁铁的南极上。
so that the north pole in the top magnet is lying over the south pole of the bottom magnet.
这是旋转电动机的基本原理。让我们重新运行前一个
This is the underlying principle of rotary electric motors. Let’s re-run the previous
例如，顶部磁铁再次旋转。而且，当它几乎处于静止状态时，我们会做什么
example and the top magnet, once again, rotates. And, when it’s nearly at rest, what we do
是我们拉扯技巧，我们扭转底部磁铁。
is we pull a trick and we reverse the bottom magnet.
所以，现在它看起来像这样。现在，顶部磁铁将继续旋转，以便它
So, now it looks like this. And now, the top magnet is going to keep rotating so that its
北极被南极吸引，然后我们再次拉同样的把戏。
north pole is attracted to the south pole and then we pull the same trick again.
因此，通过这种方式，我们可以保持顶部磁铁无限旋转，并且可以参考这个技巧
So, in this way, we can keep the top magnet rotating endlessly and this trick is referred
作为减刑。这是所有电动旋转电机的基本原理。所以这是
to as commutation. It’s a fundamental principle of all electric rotary motors. So, it’s
很像狗追尾。它永远不会到达目的地。
a lot like a dog chasing its tail. It’s never ever going to get to the destination.
当顶部磁铁接近目的地时，我们改变了目的地，我们继续这样做
When the top magnet gets close to its destination, we change the destination and we keep doing
这一遍又一遍。
this over and over again.
这是第一台电动机的照片。它于1827年在匈牙利发明。
Here is a picture of the first ever electric motor. It was invented in 1827 in Hungary.
那是近200年前的事了。现在，这个电动机的主要部件是，首先，
That’s nearly 200 years ago. Now, the principal components of this electric motor are, firstly,
定子。这是固定电磁铁，这里突出显示它已经得到了
the Stator. That’s the stationary electromagnet that’s highlighted here and it has got the
磁场矢量用红色表示。
magnetic field vector indicated in red.
现在，还有另一个电磁铁，这个电磁铁旋转。我们称之为转子，它有
Now, there is another electromagnet and this one rotates. We call it the rotor and it has
由蓝色矢量表示的磁场。磁吸引和排斥定律
a magnetic field indicated by the blue vector. The laws of magnetic attraction and repulsion
使转子旋转，使磁场对齐。当磁场
cause the rotor to rotate so that the magnetic fields are aligned. When the magnetic fields
几乎对齐，换向器反转流过电流的方向
are almost aligned, the Commutator reverses the direction of current flowing through the
转子电磁铁，它反转磁场的方向，使转子保持旋转
rotor electromagnet that reverses the direction of the magnetic field so the rotor keeps rotating
再次尝试将其磁场与定子的磁场对齐，这个过程就是
to, again, try and align its magnetic field with that of the Stator and this process is
无限期地重复。因此，换向器是允许旋转的关键创新
repeated indefinitely. So, the Commutator is the key innovation that allows a rotary
电动马达操作。
electric motor to operate.
如果我们看一下现代电动机，我们会发现它具有完全相同的组件。
If we look at a modern electric motor, we see that it has exactly the same components.
它有固定的电磁铁，我们称之为定子。它有旋转电磁铁
It has the stationary electromagnet which we call the Stator. It has the rotary electromagnet
我们称之为转子。而且，在电机的这一端，我们有了换向器。现代
which we call the rotor. And, at this end of the motor, we have the Commutator. Modern
电动机成本低，结构紧凑，性能可靠。我们可以将它们视为一种设备
electric motors are low cost, compact and reliable. We can consider them as a device
将流入电动机的电流转换为施加到输出的转矩
that converts a current flowing in to the motor in to a torque applied to the output
电动机的轴与这种关系是线性的。另一种考虑方式
shaft of the motor and this relationship is linear. An alternative way to consider an
电动机是将输入电压转换为旋转的装置
electric motor is that it is a device that converts an input voltage to a rotational
速度Ω是电机输出轴的旋转速度。
velocity omega that is the speed of rotation of the output shaft of the motor.
到目前为止我们讨论过的电机是旋转电机。那就是输出是旋转的
The motors that we have discussed so far are rotary motors. That is the output is rotary
运动。但是，经常在实际应用中，我们需要线性运动，而不是旋转运动。
motion. But, frequently, in real applications, we require linear motion, not rotary motion.
我们可以通过两种方式实现这一目标。一种是从旋转转换旋转运动
There is a couple of ways we can achieve this. One is to convert rotary motion from a rotary
电动机采用齿轮齿条机构进行直线运动。另一种选择是
electric motor to linear motion using a rack and pinion mechanism. An alternative is a
线性电动机或线性执行器。并且，在这种类型的装置中，轴移动
linear electric motor or linear actuator. And, in this type of device, the shaft moves
进出执行器的主体，有点像液压和气动执行器
in and out of the body of the actuator, somewhat like the hydraulic and pneumatic actuators
我们之前看过的。
that we looked at earlier.
这是现代电动机的一个例子。这些设备非常有效，非常可靠
Here is an example of a modern electric motor. These devices are very effective, very reliable
非常非常便宜这是一个旋转电机。所以，当我将电流传递到这些电线时，
and very, very cheap. This is a rotary motor. So, as I pass current in to these wires here,
输出轴以顺时针方向或逆时针方向旋转。
the output shaft rotates in either the clockwise or the anti-clockwise direction.
以下是集成电机和编码器组件的示例。所以，有一个直流电机
Here is an example of an integrated motor and encoder assembly. So, there is a DC motor
在前部，这是输出轴。并且，背面是增量
in the front part and this is the output shaft here. And, on the back is the incremental
编码器向控制器发出信号，指示电机的方向和速度
encoder which gives the signal to the controller about which direction and how fast the motor
转身。在这里，我们有一个更加集成的组件。这里有一台电动机。
is turning. Here we have an even more integrated assembly. This has got an electric motor here.
有一个变速箱，这是装配这一端的增量编码器。所以这
There is a gearbox and here is the incremental encoder on this end of the assembly. So, this
在机电一体化系统中的许多机器人中，在集成电机中是相当常见的设备
is quite a common device in many robots in mechatronics systems, in integrated motor
变速箱和编码器组件。
gearbox and encoder assembly.
最后，在这里，我们有一个爱好类伺服电机的例子，这是一个轮子
Finally, here, we have an example of a hobby class servo motor and this is one of the wheel
从我一直在建造的小型机器人开车。这是一个更加整合的
drives from the small robot that I have been building. This is an even more integrated
装配比我们看到的最后一个。它包含一个电动机，一个变速箱，一个
assembly than the last one we looked at. It contains an electric motor, a gearbox, an
编码器和实际控制电机和电机控制的小型计算机
encoder and a small computer which actually controls the motor and the motor controls
通过这种信号，三线电缆提供功率和速度
signals coming through this, three wire cable which provides power and also the velocity
命令信号。
command signal.